Simon Fraser University Faculty Women's Association fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Simon Fraser University Faculty Women's Association fonds
1965 - 1977
F-78
Q106642960
25 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Simon Fraser University Faculty Women's Association
The Simon Fraser University Women's Association was founded in 1965, and dissolved in 1977. The association met for the first time on March 16, 1965 under the name Simon Fraser University Women's Club. Its first objectives were to provide hospitality to new arrivals at the university, and to help with housing. Shortly afterwards the association expanded its purpose to be the encouragement of the best interests of Simon Fraser University and the general community. The management and administration of the association rested with the executive, consisting of a President, Vice-Presidents, Secretary, Treasurer, and the past President.
In 1966, the group changed its name to the Simon Fraser University Faculty Women's Association, and, in 1973, again changed its name to the Simon Fraser University Women's Association. Regular membership in the association was open to members and wives of the university's teaching or research staff, administrative staff officers, library staff, governing staff, and to other women connected to the university as approved by the association's executive.
Activities of the association included regular meetings, social activities such as outings and lectures, wine and cheese parties, and the organization of the annual Christmas party for the children of staff and faculty.
The Simon Fraser University Women's Association dissolved in 1977 due to declining membership and lack of interest in its activities.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on its provenance.
Fonds consists of records created and received by the Simon Fraser University Women's Association in carrying out its objectives. Includes constitution and by-laws, executive lists, minutes of executive and general meetings, reports, membership lists, correspondence, newsletters, mailing lists, and records reflecting the association's activities, such as the organization of the annual Christmas party.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Community life; Women
The fonds was transferred to the archives by the Simon Fraser University Women's Association in 1977.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
A file list is available.
- Constitution and By-laws, 1966 - 1967; F-78-0-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
  published
  Textual records
  Pending review
- Executive Lists, 1965 - 1974; F-78-0-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- Executive Meetings, 1966 - 1969; F-78-0-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- Executive Meetings, 1970 - 1977; F-78-0-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- President's Reports, 1967 - 1977; F-78-0-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- First Vice-President - Program Convener, 1969 - 1973; F-78-0-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- Treasurer's Report, 1965 - 1974; F-78-0-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- Treasurer's Report, 1975; F-78-0-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- Treasurer's Ledgers, 1972 - 1974; F-78-0-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- Financial Statements, 1965 - 1976; F-78-0-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- Correspondence Secretary, 1968 - 1977; F-78-0-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- General Meetings, 1965 - 1969; F-78-0-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- General Meetings, 1970 - 1975; F-78-0-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- Membership Lists, 1967 - 1977; F-78-0-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- Correspondence, 1968; F-78-0-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- Correspondence, 1968 - 1977; F-78-0-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- Correspondence - Bursary and Bridge, 1971 - 1977; F-78-0-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 78-1)
- Newsletters, 1965 - 1969; F-78-0-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 78-2)
- Newsletters, 1970 - 1977; F-78-0-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 78-2)
- Mailing Lists, 1971 - 1973; F-78-0-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 78-2)
- Christmas Parties, 1966 - 1975; F-78-0-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 78-2)
- Wine and Cheese Parties, 1973 - 1975; F-78-0-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 78-2)
- Faculty Women's Association Booklet, [ca 1967]; F-78-0-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 78-2)
- Scholarships, 1972 - 1977; F-78-0-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 78-2)
- Survey, 1967; F-78-0-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 78-2)